here's a fascinating way to approximate
the serinsky triangle with a single
curve in the
plane let's consider a relatively simple
Linden Meer system we start with the
string a and the production rules tell
us that at each stage we replace a by B-
a-b and we replace B With A + B + a and
we will let dashes and pluses stay the
same at each stage let's see the first
few stages of this process start
starting with a the first stage results
in B-
a-b then the second stage results in the
string a plus B+ a dash B- A- B Das a +
B+ a we can continue this process over
and over as long as we like each time
applying the production
rules eventually we can stop at a
particular string and we can use the
string to walk on the plane
if we see a character of A or B we will
step one unit forward in the direction
we're facing if we see a plus sign we
will rotate 60° to the left and if we
see a dash we will rotate 60° to the
right let's see what shape emerges from
this Turtle Graphics process when we
investigate the string that results
after the 10th iteration of the
production rules described by this L
system here are the first few characters
of the process let's use this string to
walk on the plane to some dramatic
[Music]
music
n
[Music]
if you liked this video check out the
links in the description for other
videos drawing other shapes using Turtle
graphics and L systems